<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog Ciberseguridad</title>
    <link>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog Ciberseguridad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 18:12:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HowToLearnBash</title>
      <link>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/howtolearnbash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 18:12:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/howtolearnbash/</guid>
      <description>GNU Bash (Bourne-again shell) is a command-line user interface, specifically a Unix shell and a scripting language. This is very useful tool for cibersecurity and I&amp;rsquo;m going to recommend some useful resources, to learn bash with practice and no theoretical.
Bandit - Over the wire https://overthewire.org/wargames/bandit/ is a web page with the instructions to connect via SSH to the server and here you have to look for the password for the next level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local File Inclusion (LFI)</title>
      <link>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/localfileinclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 18:13:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/localfileinclusion/</guid>
      <description>Definici칩n Se trata de la vulnerabilidad que afecta a muchos servidores web que permite accedera archivos que no quieren que sean expuestos.
Peligros F치cil acceso a archivos confidenciales, el m치s com칰n /etc/passwd
LFI, 쮸 qu칠 se debe? Para poder pr치cticar y entender mejor esta vulnerabilidad recomiendo usar la m치quina bts_lab que cuenta con m칰ltiples vulnerabilidades para aprender pentesting web, es f치cil de instalar en kali linux o una m치quina de ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password managers</title>
      <link>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/passwordmanagers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 10:23:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/passwordmanagers/</guid>
      <description>Passwords Managers are a great tool to keep save your passwords and many other things. Most browsers have their own native password managers, which store all the passwords you use on the Internet to remind you when you go to log in to your different pages both on the computer and on other devices where you have them installed. However, these managers are quite basic and have practically no options beyond reminding you of your passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android vs IOS</title>
      <link>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/android-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 09:58:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/android-ios/</guid>
      <description>Android or iOS 游꼝游뛿릯, what is safer? Siempre se ha dicho los iPhones son m치s seguros que los dispositivos con sistemas basados en Android, pero realmente es as칤?. En este post vamos a tratar de ver las diferencias entre los SO m치s usados en el 치mbito de la seguridad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/primer-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 12:05:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosemill.github.io/blog-ciberseguridad/posts/primer-post/</guid>
      <description>Este es un blog hecho con el generador de sitios est치ticos HUGO. La intenci칩n de este blog, en el 치mbito personal, es el aprendizaje de publicar p치ginas web de manera sencilla y seguir form치ndome en 치mbito de la tecnolog칤a, adem치s de compartir todo lo que aprenda en este proceso.
Espero que te guste. 游뱔</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
